<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Borrow Money Info</string>

    <string name="app_intro">You can use in 100+ country and 4000+ city on just instant loan. You can change your interest and tenure anytime from anywhere</string>

    <string name="app_name_"><font fgcolor='#428ACC'>Borrow</font><font fgcolor='#000'> Money Info</font></string>

    <string name="share_app_message">Loan advise using this app. Download Now</string>
    <string name="want_to_exit"><font fgcolor='#000'>Exit</font><font fgcolor='#FF0000'>\nAre you sure</font><font fgcolor='#000'>\nyou want to exit?</font></string>
    <string name="locate_office">✤ Visit the EPFO website and click on the “Locate an EPFO Office” option.\n✤ Alternatively, click on the link http://search.epfoservices.org:81/locate_office/office_location.php to find EPFO offices directly.\n✤ In case you want to know the EPF office having jurisdiction over an address, select the first option.\n✤ Now select your state or union territory from the drop down list and select the district where you want to locate the EPF office.\n✤ Results will be displayed containing the details of the regional office and the office under whose administrative control the office is operating.\n✤ In case you want to know the jurisdiction of an EPF office, then click on the second option and select the office from the drop down menu and click on the submit button. The result displayed contains the complete address of the office and e-mail address of concerned authorities.\n✤ Results are displayed on the screen mentioning the state, district, jurisdiction area and the jurisdiction status of the office.</string>
    <string name="balance_online">✤ Log in to the EPFO website and click on the Our Services tab.\n✤ Choose the For Employees option from the drop-down menu.\n✤On the login page, enter the username which is the UAN and password to log in.\n✤Once logged in, employees can access their EPF details.\n✤Click on the respective passbook to check your EPF balance with different employers.</string>

    <string name="Activate_UNA">✤ Ways to Check EPF Balance Online\n✤The EPFO has been introducing new methods for employees to check the EPF balance and is in the process of developing the existing platforms that can be used.\n✤ Online Portal\n✤ SMS Service\n✤ Missed Call</string>
    <string name="Pensioners">✤ EPFO introduced a new system to facilitate online submission of transfer claims by Members with an objective to make the transfer process transparent, efficient and comfortable for your employees.\n✤ You are urged to bring this facility to the notice of all your employees which is available on EPFOs Member portal.\n✤ A member has an option to submit his claim either through his present employer or the previous one.\n✤ You can see all such claim requests with ease, verify/correct member details, approve and submit the requests online through this portal.\n✤ For online submission of the claims, the Digital signature (Class II or above) of the authorized person is required.</string>
    <string name="TRRN_Status">✤ Visit the EPF Portal and click on ‘Our Services’ on the dashboard and click on For Employees.\n✤ Click on Member Passbook\n✤ The following details must be populated to log in to access the account.</string>
    <string name="FAQ">✤ EPFO Recruitment 2019 Free Job alert for both Fresher and Experienced Candidates updated on March 12, 2019.\n✤ Get Direct Official Link for applying EPFO Recruitment 2019 along with current EPFO Recruitment official Notification 2019 here.\n✤ Find all recent EPFO Vacancy 2019 across India and check all latest EPFO 2019 job openings instantly here, Know upcoming EPFO Recruitment 2019 immediately here.</string>
    <string name="YourClaimStatus">✤ Step 1: Login to the Unified Portal of Employees’ Provident Fund (https://unifiedportal.epfindia.gov.in/) and click on For employees, followed by UAN Member e-Sewa.\n✤ Step 2: Enter UAN and password to log in to the portal.\n✤ Step 3: Click on Manage on the top panel and then on KYC\n✤ Step 4: On the next page, under Add KYC tab, provide your bank, PAN and Aadhaar, passport, driving license, election card and ration card details. Then click on submit. After submitting, you can find these details under Pending KYC tab. Once approved by the employer (which would generally take 15 days), it will be shown under Approved KYC tab.\n✤ Linking of your Aadhaar to EPF account will help in faster withdrawal and transfer process and for that, the present employer should have approved and verified the KYC including the employees Aadhaar details.</string>


    <string name="epf_online_title10_detail">✤ View all Tender Notifications issued by Employees Provident Fund Organisation.\n✤ Search live eProcurement business opportunities available in EPFO Tenders section.\n✤ Employees Provident Fund Organisation Tenders are further filtered by Bid Submission Date, Tender Value, Project Location and Product Category.\n✤Get email alert on Tenders from Employees Provident Fund Organisation - (EPFO).</string>
    <string name="epf_online_title11_detail">✤ Step 1: Login to the Unified Portal of Employees’ Provident Fund (https://unifiedportal.epfindia.gov.in/) and click on For employees, followed by UAN Member e-Sewa.\n✤ Step 2: Enter UAN and password to log in to the portal.\n✤ Step 3: Click on Manage on the top panel and then on KYC\n✤ Step 4: On the next page, under Add KYC tab, provide your bank, PAN and Aadhaar, passport, driving license, election card and ration card details. Then click on submit. After submitting, you can find these details under Pending KYC tab. Once approved by the employer (which would generally take 15 days), it will be shown under Approved KYC tab.\n✤ Linking of your Aadhaar to EPF account will help in faster withdrawal and transfer process and for that, the present employer should have approved and verified the KYC including the employees Aadhaar details.</string>
    <string name="epf_online_title12_detail">✤ EPF 24×7 Customer Care Number and Toll Free Helpline- Employee Provident Fund\n✤ And Head Office Address List Are Blow Plz Click The Button.</string>
    <string name="epf_online_title1_detail">✤ Ways to Check EPF Balance Online\n✤The EPFO has been introducing new methods for employees to check the EPF balance and is in the process of developing the existing platforms that can be used.\n✤ Online Portal\n✤ SMS Service\n✤ Missed Call</string>
    <string name="epf_online_title2_detail">✤ Step 1: Go to the EPFO portal. Click on Our services&gt; For Employees\n✤ Step 2: Click on Know Your PF Status\n✤ Step 3: Enter your UAN and enter the captcha image\n✤ Step 4: Enter the following details\n➺ Enter the state of your PF office\n➺ Select your PF Office from the drop-down menu\n➺ Enter your establishment code\n➺ Enter your Provident Fund account number\n✤ Step 5: Click on the Submit button to check the status of your PF claim.</string>
    <string name="epf_online_title3_detail">✤ EPFO introduced a new system to facilitate online submission of transfer claims by Members with an objective to make the transfer process transparent, efficient and comfortable for your employees.\n✤ You are urged to bring this facility to the notice of all your employees which is available on EPFOs Member portal.\n✤ A member has an option to submit his claim either through his present employer or the previous one.\n✤ You can see all such claim requests with ease, verify/correct member details, approve and submit the requests online through this portal.\n✤ For online submission of the claims, the Digital signature (Class II or above) of the authorized person is required.</string>
    <string name="epf_online_title4_detail">✤ Visit the EPF Portal and click on ‘Our Services’ on the dashboard and click on For Employees.\n✤ Click on Member Passbook\n✤ The following details must be populated to log in to access the account.</string>
    <string name="epf_online_title5_detail">✤ Types of EPF Claim Forms\n✤ Form 19: This is to be filled in case of final settlement of PF account by a member.\n✤ Form 10C: This is to be filled for claiming Scheme Certificate/Withdrawal Benefit as per Employees’ Pension Scheme 95.\n✤ Form 10D: This is to be filled for pension claims.\n✤ Form 20: This is to be filled for claiming PF by legal heir/nominee on death of a member.\n✤ Form 5IF: This is to be filled for claiming assurance benefit as per Employees Deposit Linked Insurance 76 by legal heir/nominee of a member.\n✤ Form 31: For claiming advance/temporary withdrawal as per Employees Provident Scheme 52.\n✤ Form 13: For transferring PF/pension between different accounts.\n✤ Form 14: For financing a life insurance policy out of the PF account</string>
    <string name="epf_online_title6_detail">✤ Multiple job changes typically result in multiple Employee Provident Fund (EPF) accounts being opened, one with each employer.\n✤ With the introduction of the UAN (Universal Account Number), it is possible to consolidate multiple accounts into one single account for each EPFO member.\n✤ Retirement fund body EPFO offers a facility to its members that allows consolidation or merger of their multiple PF accounts with the current universal account number (UAN).</string>
    <string name="epf_online_title7_detail">✤ To avail the e-Passbook facility, you will have to compulsorily register on the EPFO official website. The following details will have to be filled in while registering:\n➺ Your mobile number\n➺ PAN number\n➺ Aadhar Card number\n➺ National Population Register number\n➺ Bank account number\n➺ Voter ID\n➺ Driving license\n➺ Passport number\n➺ Ration Card number\n➺ Your name as on the official documents\n➺ Email ID\n➺ You will get a captcha image, which you must type in the box provided and you will get the PIN.\n➺ The PIN will be received on your registered mobile number via SMS. After you submit the form, you will get a confirmation on your registered mobile and it completes the registration process.\n✤ You can then login to the EPFO Member Portal and check your EPF status online.\n✤ The following is the process to generate your EPF e-Passbook:\n➺ Once you have logged in to the member portal, you will get a screen that you can alter your details and also download e-Passbook from this page.\n➺ When you select download, you will be asked to select the state and you will have to select the PF office of that state.\n➺ If you have no idea which is your PF office, you can find the details at http://epf-india.co.in/ .\n➺ You can then enter the EPF account number and your name that is the same as in your EPFO records.\n➺ Fill in the captcha details and avail the PIN number.\n➺ Enter the pin number that you receive on your registered mobile number via SMS.\n➺ Finally hit the button – Get Detail. You can then download the PDF e-Passbook.\n✤ Remember the following while downloading EPF e-Passbook:\n➺ Only one mobile number can be used for one registration.\n➺ You can however edit the mobile number later on.\n➺ You can see only one EPF account under one establishment.\n➺ You can transfer old EPF account to the new one.\n➺ You will not be able to see settled or inoperative accounts.\n➺ You can register using different ID proofs and mobile number to check the details of the different accounts.\n➺ Your EPF e-Passbook will contain the month and date wise transactions made in your account from the year in which the annual accounts were updated for the establishment.</string>
    <string name="epf_online_title8_detail">✤ Types of EPF Claim Forms\n✤ Form 19: This is to be filled in case of final settlement of PF account by a member.\n✤ Form 10C: This is to be filled for claiming Scheme Certificate/Withdrawal Benefit as per Employees Pension Scheme 95.\n✤ Form 10D: This is to be filled for pension claims.\n✤ Form 20: This is to be filled for claiming PF by legal heir/nominee on death of a member.\n✤ Form 5IF: This is to be filled for claiming assurance benefit as per Employees Deposit Linked Insurance 76 by legal heir/nominee of a member.\n✤ Form 31: For claiming advance/temporary withdrawal as per Employees Provident Scheme 52.\n✤ Form 13: For transferring PF/pension between different accounts.\n✤ Form 14: For financing a life insurance policy out of the PF account</string>
    <string name="epf_online_title9_detail">✤ EPFO Recruitment 2019 Free Job alert for both Fresher and Experienced Candidates updated on March 12, 2019.\n✤ Get Direct Official Link for applying EPFO Recruitment 2019 along with current EPFO Recruitment official Notification 2019 here.\n✤ Find all recent EPFO Vacancy 2019 across India and check all latest EPFO 2019 job openings instantly here, Know upcoming EPFO Recruitment 2019 immediately here.</string>


    <string name="link_Activate_UAN">https://passbook.epfindia.gov.in/MemberPassBook/Login.jsp</string>
    <string name="link_BalanceOnline">https://passbook.epfindia.gov.in/MemberPassBook/Login.jsp</string>
    <string name="link_Check_Your_EPF">https://epfindia.gov.in/site_en/</string>
    <string name="link_Download_Claim_Form">https://www.epfindia.gov.in/site_en/Downloads.php?id=sm8_index</string>
    <string name="link_Downloads">https://www.epfindia.gov.in/site_en/Downloads.php?id=sm8_index</string>
    <string name="link_E_Passbook">https://passbook.epfindia.gov.in/MemberPassBook/Login.jsp</string>
    <string name="link_FAQs">http://pfapp.mypfbalance.com/faq.html</string>
    <string name="link_Locate_Office">http://search.epfoservices.org:81/locate_office/office_location.php</string>
    <string name="link_Member_Passbook">https://passbook.epfindia.gov.in/MemberPassBook/Login.jsp</string>
    <string name="link_Multiple_PF_Accounts_of_an_Employee">https://passbook.epfindia.gov.in/MemberPassBook/Login.jsp</string>
    <string name="link_News">https://news.google.com/news/search/section/q/employee%20provident%20fund/employee%20provident%20fund?hl=en&amp;gl=US&amp;ned=us</string>
    <string name="link_Online_Transfer_Claims_Portal_OTCP">https://www.epfindia.gov.in/site_en/OTCP_ForEmployers.php</string>
    <string name="link_Pensioners">https://mis.epfindia.gov.in/PensionPaymentEnquiry/</string>
    <string name="link_RTI">https://www.epfindia.gov.in/site_en/RTI.php?id=sm12_index</string>
    <string name="link_Recruitments">https://www.epfindia.gov.in/site_en/Recruitments.php?id=sm9_index</string>
    <string name="link_TRRN_status">https://unifiedportal-epfo.epfindia.gov.in/publicPortal/no-auth/misReport/home/loadSearchTrrnHome</string>
    <string name="link_contact_US">https://www.epfindia.gov.in/site_en/Contact_us.php</string>
    <string name="linnk_Tenders">https://www.epfindia.gov.in/site_en/Tender_Auction.php?id=sm10_index</string>
    <string name="cliam_link">tps://www.epfindia.gov.in/site_en/Downloads.php?id=sm8_index</string>


    <string name="inform_1">Simply put , it is an unsecured loan taken by individuals from a bank or a non - banking financial company ( NBFC ) to meet their personal needs .  It is provided on the basis of key criteria such as income level, credit and employment history, repayment capacity, etc.  \n\n→ Unlike a home or a car loan, a personal loan is not secured against any asset.  As it is unsecured and the borrower does not put up collateral like gold or property to avail it , the lender , in case of a default , cannot auction. Simply put , it is an unsecured loan taken by individuals from a bank or a non -  banking financial company ( NBFC ) to meet their personal needs .  \n\n→ It is provided on the basis of key criteria such as income level, credit and employment history, repayment capacity, etc.  Unlike a home or a car loan, a personal loan is not secured against any asset.  \n\n→ As it is unsecured and the borrower does not put up collateral like gold or property to avail it , the lender , in case of a default , cannot auction .  Simply put , it is an unsecured loan taken by individuals from a bank or a non - banking financial company ( NBFC ) to meet their personal needs .  \n\n→ It is provided on the basis of key criteria such as income level, credit and employment history, repayment capacity, etc.  Unlike a home or a car loan, a personal loan is not secured against any asset.  As it is unsecured and the borrower does not put up collateral like gold or property to avail it , the lender , in case of a default , cannot auction , \n\n→ Simply put , it is an unsecured loan taken by individuals from a bank or a non  - banking financial company ( NBFC ) to meet their personal needs .  It is provided on the basis of key criteria such as income level, credit and employment history, repayment capacity, etc.  Unlike a home or a car loan, a personal loan is not secured against any asset.  \n\n→ As it is unsecured and the borrower does not put up collateral like gold or property to avail it , the lender , in case of a default , cannot auction .</string>
    <string name="inform_2">Borrow Money Info fff - It can be used for any personal financial need and the bank will not monitor its use .  a \n\n→ It can be utilized for renovating your home , marriage - related expenses , family vacation , your child\'s education , purchasing latest electronic gadgets or home appliances , meeting unexpected medical expenses any other emergencies .  or \n\n→ Personal loans are also useful when it comes to investing in business, fixing your car, down payment of new house, etc.</string>
    <string name="inform_3">Although it varies from bank to bank, the general criteria include your age, occupation, income, ability to repay the loan and place of residence.  To avail of a personal loan, you must have a regular income source, whether you are a salaried individual, self-employed business person or a professional.  An individuals eligibility is also affected by the company he is employed with, his credit history, etc.</string>
    <string name="inform_4">It usually depends on your income and varies based on whether you are salaried or self - employed .  Usually, the banks restrict the loan amount such that your EMI is not more than 40-50% of your monthly income.  \n\n→ Any existing loans that are being serviced by the applicant are also considered when calculating the personal loan amount .  > For the self employed , the loan value is determined on the basis of the profit earned as per the most recently acknowledged profit / loss statement , while taking into ac ...</string>
    <string name="inform_5">It is good to compare the offers of various banks before you settle on one .  Some key factors to consider when deciding on a loan provider include interest rates, loan tenure, processing fees, etc.</string>
    <string name="inform_6">Although the loan sanctioning criteria may differ from one bank to another , some key factors determining the maximum loan amount that can be sanctioned to you include your credit score , current income level as well as liabilities .  \n\n→ A high credit score ( closer to 900 ) means you have serviced your previous loans and / or credit card dues properly , leading the lenders to feel that you are a safe borrower , leading to a higher loan amount being sanctioned .  Your current income level and liability ..</string>
    <string name="inform_7">Being unsecured loans , personal loans have a higher interest rate than those on secured home and car loans .  \n\n→ At present, many leading banks and NBFCs offer such loans at interest rates of as low as 11.49%.  However , the rate applicable to a borrower is contingent on key factors , including credit score , income level , loan amount and tenure , previous relationship ( savings account , loans or credit cards ) with the lender , etc.</string>
    <string name="inform_8">Though the documentation requirements vary from one financial institution to another, some key documents you will have to provide with your personal loan application include: * Income proof (salary slip for salaried / recently acknowledged ITR for self-employed ) * Address proof documents * Identity  proof documents * Certified copies of degree / license ( in case of self - employed individuals )</string>
    <string name="inform_9">Part payment : This amount is less than the full loan principal amount and is made before the loan amount becomes due .  * Prepayment : When you pay off your loan in part before it becomes due as per the EMI schedule.  – The prepayment amount may or may not be equal to the total due amount .  Prepayment charges are usually in 2-5 % range of the outstanding loan amount .  - Additionally , many banks do not allow prepayment / preclosure of loan before a specified number of EMIs have been completed .  * Preclosure : It refers to completely paying off a personal loan before the loan tenure has ended.  Just like prepayment charge , preclosure charges range from 2-5 % of the loan amount .</string>
    <string name="inform_10">→ The approval is at the sole discretion of the loan sanctioning officer whose decision is based on the criteria specified by the bank / financial institution \n\n→ The entire process can take between 48 hours and about two weeks.  Once all the necessary documents are submitted and the verification process is completed , the loan , if sanctioned , is disbursed within seven working days by the bank .  \n\n→ Do keep all necessary documents ready along with PDC and / or signed ECS form to avoid delays in loan processing .. </string>
    <string name="inform_11">→ Since a personal loan is an unsecured loan , therefore your credit history usually plays a significant role in the approval process .  Equifax , Experian and CIBIL TransUnion are the three credit reporting agencies that operate in India .  - All 3 have tie - ups with lenders and provide their credit rating services to help lenders evaluate prospective borrowers .  \n\n→ Experian India has collaboration with Union Bank of India , Sundaram Finance , Punjab National Bank , Magna Finance , Indian Bank , Axis Ba ..</string>
    <string name="inform_12">→ A higher credit score indicates that you have a good track record with respect to loans .  \n\n→ Therefore, if your credit score is high (more than 750 in case of CIBIL TransUnion), your chances of being granted a loan are much.  \n\n→ Additionally , you may be able to negotiate benefits such as a lower interest rate , higher loan amount , waiver of processing charges , etc.  , by leveraging your high credit score.</string>


    <string name="InstantLoanadvise1">Simply put, it is an unsecured loan taken by individuals from a bank or a non-banking financial company (NBFC) to meet their personal needs. It is provided on the basis of key criteria such as income level, credit and employment history, repayment capacity, etc.\n➺ Unlike a home or a car loan, a personal loan is not secured against any asset. As it is unsecured and the borrower does not put up collateral like gold or property to avail it, the lender, in case of a default, cannot auction.Simply put, it is an unsecured loan taken by individuals from a bank or a non-banking financial company (NBFC) to meet their personal needs.\n➺ It is provided on the basis of key criteria such as income level, credit and employment history, repayment capacity, etc. Unlike a home or a car loan, a personal loan is not secured against any asset.\n➺ As it is unsecured and the borrower does not put up collateral like gold or property to avail it, the lender, in case of a default, cannot auction.Simply put, it is an unsecured loan taken by individuals from a bank or a non-banking financial company (NBFC) to meet their personal needs.\n➺ It is provided on the basis of key criteria such as income level, credit and employment history, repayment capacity, etc. Unlike a home or a car loan, a personal loan is not secured against any asset. As it is unsecured and the borrower does not put up collateral like gold or property to avail it, the lender, in case of a default, cannot auction.\n➺ Simply put, it is an unsecured loan taken by individuals from a bank or a non-banking financial company (NBFC) to meet their personal needs. It is provided on the basis of key criteria such as income level, credit and employment history, repayment capacity, etc. Unlike a home or a car loan, a personal loan is not secured against any asset.\n➺ As it is unsecured and the borrower does not put up collateral like gold or property to avail it, the lender, in case of a default, cannot auction.</string>
    <string name="InstantLoanadvise2">It can be used for any personal financial need and the bank will not monitor its use.\n➺ It can be utilised for renovating your home, marriage-related expenses, a family vacation, your childs education, purchasing latest electronic gadgets or home appliances, meeting unexpected medical expenses or any other emergencies.\n➺ Personal loans are also useful when it comes to investing in business, fixing your car, down payment of new house, etc.</string>
    <string name="InstantLoanadvise3">Although it varies from bank to bank, the general criteria include your age, occupation, income, capacity to repay the loan and place of residence. To avail of a personal loan, you must have a regular income source, whether you are a salaried individual, self-employed business person or a professional.\n➺ An individuals eligibility is also affected by the company he is employed with, his credit history, etc.</string>
    <string name="InstantLoanadvise4">It usually depends on your income and varies based on whether you are salaried or self–employed. Usually, the banks restrict the loan amount such that your EMI is not more than 40–50% of your monthly income.\n➺ Any existing loans that are being serviced by the applicant are also considered when calculating the personal loan amount.\n➺ For the self employed, the loan value is determined on the basis of the profit earned as per the most recent acknowledged profit/Loss statement, while taking into ac…</string>
    <string name="InstantLoanadvise5">It is good to compare the offers of various banks before you settle on one. Some key factors to consider when deciding on a loan provider include interest rates, loan tenure, processing fees, etc.</string>
    <string name="InstantLoanadvise6">Although the loan sanctioning criteria may differ from one bank to another, some key factors determining the maximum loan amount that can be sanctioned to you include your credit score, current income level as well as liabilities.\n➺ A high credit score (closer to 900) means you have serviced your previous loans and/or credit card dues properly, leading the lenders to feel that you are a safe borrower, leading to a higher loan amount being sanctioned. Your current income level and liabil ..</string>


    <string name="text">आधार कार्ड से ऑनलाइन लोन लेने के लिए कैसे अप्लाई करें आज के समय में एक ऐसी ID बहुत ज्यादा चलती है जोकि आज के समय बहुत ही फेमस ID हो चुकी है हां दोस्तों हम बात करें आधार कार्ड की आधार कार्ड में कैसे ID है जो कि किसी भी जगह किसी भी तरह की ID के लिए आप दे सकते हैं और यह आपकी संपूर्ण ID मानी जाती है आधार कार्ड के आधार पर आप किसी भी तरह की कोई भी चीज को उपलब्ध करवा सकते हैं और किसी से भी आधार कार्ड के जरिए आप कुछ भी ले सकते हैं अपना सिम ले सकते हैं या अपने बैंक अकाउंट खुलवा सकते हैं  लोन ले सकते हैं गाड़ी ले सकते हैं गैस सिलेंडर ले सकते हैं और अपने किसी भी तरह के डाक्यूमेंट्स के अंदर आप आधार कार्ड को शामिल कर सकते हैं यह भारतीय सरकार का एक बहुत ही बड़ा फायदा यह है कि अगर आप किसी चीज को आधार कार्ड नंबर के आधार पर लेते हैं तो जब आप की चीज गुम हो जाती है या किसी कारणवश कहीं पर छूट जाती है तो उसके बाद आप उस चीज को अपने आधार कार्ड के साथ दोबारा से पा सकते हैं आधार कार्ड एक ऐसी चीज है जो कि आप हर चीज में यूज करते हैं जैसे आप अगर मोबाइल की सिम लेते हैं और अगर आप अपनी सिम को जल्दी शुरू करवाना चाहते हैं तो उसके लिए आप अपने आधार नंबर को दुकानदार को दीजिए और फिर वह दुकानदार आपको आपके हाथ में किसी भी उंगली को अपनी मशीन पर रखो आएगा जिससे की आपके हाथ के जो निशान है वह उस मशीन में आ जाएंगे और फिर आप के आधार कार्ड का वेरीफाई हो जाएगा और उससे आप अपनी सिम को बहुत ही जल्दी शुरू करवा सकते हैं क्योंकि जब आप अपने फिगर को मशीन पर रखेंगे तो वह SIM देने वाली कंपनी के मुख्यालय तक जाते हैं जहां से अभी तुरंत ही अपनी बीवी SIM को चालू कर देते हैं और पहले जब आप ID देते थे उसके बाद तीन चार दिन के बाद कंपनी के मुख्यालय तक वह ID पहुंचती थी उसके बाद आपकी SIM शुरू होती थी इसलिए आजकल ऑनलाइन किसी भी काम को करवाने के लिए भी आधार कार्ड बहुत ही फायदेमंद साबित हो रहा है. और आजकल तो लगभग सभी सरकारी और प्राइवेट कामों के लिए आधार कार्ड होना बहुत ही जरुरी है अगर अगर आपके पास आधार कार्ड नहीं है तो आप को किसी भी सरकारी या प्राइवेट काम को करवाने के लिए बहुत दिक्कत का सामना करना पड़ सकता है क्योंकि आज के समय में आधार कार्ड सभी जगह पर मांगा जाता है आज के समय में आधार कार्ड का बहुत ही ज्यादा महत्व है. आपने वैसे तो बहुत सी तरह के लोन के बारे में सुना होगा ,होम लोन, गाड़ी के लिए लोन, या किसी तरह की कृषि यंत्र के लिए लोन बहुत अच्छी तरह के लोन पर सरकार द्वारा दिए जाते हैं लेकिन आपने शायद यह कभी भी नहीं सुना होगा कि आधार कार्ड से लोन जी हां दोस्तों आज हम आपको इस पोस्ट में आधार कार्ड से लोन लेने के बारे में जानकारी देंगे क्योंकि आप अपने आधार कार्ड से भी लोन ले सकते हैं वह भी पूरे 25 लाख रुपए तक का.</string>
    <string name="text1">आधार नंबर की मदद से मोबाइल फोन कनेक्शन, रसोई गैस कनेक्शन, और बैंकिंग जैसी उपयोगी सेवाओं का लाभ उठा सकते हैं। प्रारंभिक चरणों में यह संख्या केवल सरकार द्वारा संचालित सेवाओं को लागू करती है। मगर ये उम्मीद की जा सकती है कि भविष्य में अन्य समान सेवाओं एवं गैर-सरकारी संस्थाओं द्वारा संचालित सभी सेवायें भी इसके दायरे में आ जाएंगी। हालांकि अभी तक लोन लेने वालों के लिए आधार कार्ड देना अनिवार्य नहीं किया गया है, फिर भी यह लोन प्रोसेसिंग को बहुत आसान बना सकता है। आधार कार्ड को आईडी प्रूफ के रूप में स्वीकार करने के बाद ऋण आवेदक के दस्तावेजों को सत्यापित करने के लिए बैंक अधिकारियों को जो समय और प्रयास करना था, वह काफी कम हो गया है। आधार कार्ड को आधारभूत दस्तावेज के रूप में लेकर ऑनलाइन ऋणों में ग्राहक का सत्यापन ई-केवाईसी के साथ किया जाता है। ऋण में आधार कार्ड का उपयोग आधुनिक ऋण देने का आधार है। ई-केवाईसी के माध्यम से आवेदक के ऑनलाइन सत्यापन की वजह से तात्कालिक ऋण जो घंटों के भीतर वितरित किए जाने का दावा किया जाता है, संभव हो जाता है। ऑनलाइन ऋण जिन्हें बेहतर ऋण के रूप में जाना जाता है, को पहचान के लिए एकमात्र दस्तावेज के रूप में अपने आधार कार्ड की स्कैन की हुई कॉपी को साझा करके भी प्राप्त किया जा सकता है।</string>
    <string name="text10">1. ये लोन लेने के लिये व्यक्ति का‌ भारतीय होना अनिवार्य है। 2. अन्य बैंक से आधार कार्ड पर लोन लिया हुआ नहीं होना चाहिए। 3. लोन लेने‌ वाले व्यक्ति के पास bank passbook, aadhar card , pan card होना आवश्यक हैं। 4. लोन लेने वाला व्यक्ति लोन चुकाने‌ मे सक्षम होना चाहिए 5. लोन‌ लेने वाले‌ व्यक्ति कि उम्र 18 वर्ष या इससे अधिक होनी आवश्यक है</string>
    <string name="text11">Most important benefits of Aadhaar. Listed below are the most important benefits of Aadhaar (12 digit unique identity number). Aadhaar based Direct Benefit Transfer (LPG Subsidy) : The 12 digit individual identification number on Aadhar card is used to get LPG subsidy amount directly in the bank account. 1. LPG Subsidy 2. Jan Dhan Yojana 3. Passport in 10 days 4. Digital Locker 5. Voter Card Linking 6. Monthly Pension 7. Provident Fund 8. Opening new bank account</string>
    <string name="text12">1.सबसे पहले आपको अपने किसी ब्राउज़र से आधार हाउसिंग वेबसाइट पर जाना है. 2. इसके बाद जब आपके ब्राउज़र में वेबसाइट ओपन हो जाए तब आपको लेफ्ट साइड में अप्लाई फॉर लोन के ऊपर कलेक्ट करना है. 3. इसके बाद आप अगले पेज पर जाओगे वहां पर आपको लोन के लिए एक फार्म उत्पन्न हुआ हो मिलेगा उसके अंदर आपको अपनी सारी डिटेल भरनी है. 4.उसके बाद आप का सही नाम और आपकी ईमेल ID इसके अंदर भरनी है. 5. आपको ऐसे मोबाइल नंबर को उसके अंदर भरना है जो कि आपके पास हर समय उपलब्ध रहता  हो. 6. अगर आप किसी कंपनी में या किसी फैक्ट्री या किसी भी तरह के ऑफिस में काम करते हैं तो आप वहां का लैंडलाइन नंबर भी ऐड कर सकते हैं. 7. उसके बाद आपको आपकी सही जन्म तारीख और आपके शहर का नाम और आपके राज्य का नाम भरना है. 8.उसके बाद आप अपने नजदीक के आधार कार्ड ऑफिस को भरें और फिर आप अपना सही एड्रेस भरे जहां पर आप रहते हैं. 9.उसके बाद आप आपके क्षेत्र का पिन कोड भरेंगे. फिर आपको उसके अंदर यह भरना है कि आप क्या काम करते हैं. 10. उसके बाद आपको यह भरना है कि आप किस काम के लिए आधार लोन लेना चाहते हैं. जैसे फ्लैट लोन, गृह ऋण, गृह नवीकरण, इनमे से कुछ चीजों के लिए. 11.फिर आपको यह करना है कि आप आधार कार्ड से कितने रुपए तक का लोन लेना चाहते हैं और उसके अंदर आपको रुपए भरने हैं 12. फिर आपको आपकी एक महीने की कितनी कमाई है वह भरना है. 13. फिर आपको यह बताना है कि आपको आधार लोन कितने दिन बाद चाहिए 3 महीने 6 महीने या 1 साल बाद इनमें से आपको कुछ एक भरना होता है. 14. और फिर लास्ट में आपको यह भरना है कि आप किस समय उनका कॉल ले सकते हैं यानी कि आप उनके कॉल को किस समय  अटेंड कर सकते हैं उस बारे में आपको समय भरना है. फिर जब आप यह सारी जानकारी लेते हैं तो उसके बाद आपकी सारी चीजें पूरी हो जाती है और फिर आप उन्हें एक बार अच्छी तरह से देख कर चेक कर कर सबमिट के ऊपर क्लिक कर दें और जब आपका यह फॉर्म ऑनलाइन आधार लोन के लिए सफल हो जाएगा तो उसके बाद आपको आपके 15 दिन के बाद आपको आपके नजदीकी आधार ऑफिस के अंदर बुलाया जाएगा जो कि आपने इस फोन के अंदर भरा था फिर वहां पर आप उसे आधार ऑफिस के अधिकारी पूरी तरह से जानकारी लेंगे.</string>
    <string name="text13">यदि आधार कार्ड के माध्यम से आधार कार्ड लोन प्राप्त करना चाहते हैं। तो आप बड़ी आसानी से आधार कार्ड के माध्यम से लोन प्राप्त कर सकते हैं । Aadhar Card Home Loan लिए आपको ऑनलाइन या ऑफलाइन किसी एक तरीके से आवेदन करने के लिए निचे दी हुई वेबसाइट की विजिट करे aadharhousing[dot]com.</string>
    <string name="text14">आधार हाउसिंग फाइनेंस द्वारा पेश किए गए होम लोन की चुकौती अवधि क्या है? ग्राहक 5 वर्ष से 30 वर्ष की अवधि के भीतर ऋण का भुगतान करना चुन सकते हैं। पुनर्भुगतान की अवधि ऋण के लिए कार्यकाल 2 साल से शुरू होता है और 6 साल तक बढ़ सकता है उदाहरण के लिए, यदि आप रुपये का ऋण लेते हैं। 3 साल के पुनर्भुगतान के साथ 13% की दर से 3 लाख, आपकी ईएमआई रु। 10,108। 3 वर्षों के अंत में कुल देय राशि रु। 3,63,895। इसलिए, आप 63,895 रुपये की कुल ब्याज राशि का भुगतान कर रहे हैं। हालाँकि, यह अन्य लागू शुल्कों को शामिल करता है जिन्हें निम्न प्रकार से निर्धारित किया जा सकता है: ऋण प्रसंस्करण शुल्क - 2% प्रलेखन शुल्क</string>
    <string name="text15">यह प्रति माह ₹ 5,000 के रूप में मामूली के रूप में वेतन के साथ ग्राहकों को पूरा करता है। आधार हाउसिंग फाइनेंस में होम लोन के लिए वेतनभोगी आवेदक ग्रेड III और IV सरकारी कर्मचारियों, निजी कंपनी के कर्मचारियों, रेलवे कर्मचारियों, शिक्षकों, साथ ही पुलिस और रक्षा बलों के हैं। जबकि कंपनी के स्व-नियोजित होम लोन ग्राहकों की सूची में किराना दुकान के मालिक, छोटे विक्रेता, प्लंबर, बढ़ई, उन लोगों के साथ शामिल हैं जो कपड़ों, स्टेशनरी, पुस्तकों, कपड़े, मोबाइल और अन्य के व्यवसाय में शामिल हैं। आधार हाउसिंग फाइनेंस आपको मासिक आय, बचत, संपत्ति मूल्य, क्रेडिट इतिहास, रोजगार की स्थिति या व्यवसाय की स्थिरता जैसे कारकों के आधार पर होम लोन प्रदान करता है। होम लोन की कुल लागत आइए एक दृष्टांत की मदद से होम लोन पात्रता कैलकुलेटर के काम को समझें। मान लें कि आप say 30,000 के मासिक वेतन के साथ शीर्ष पायदान की फर्म में काम कर रहे हैं। यदि हम कहते हैं, आप अपनी मासिक आय का 40% खर्च करते हैं, तो आप ,000 18,000 की बचत के साथ समाप्त होते हैं। बचत के आधार पर, पात्रता कैलकुलेटर ऋण पात्रता राशि पर पहुंच जाएगा। राशि की गणना करते समय, वित्त कंपनी सबसे पहले ब्याज और ऋण अवधि की मौजूदा दर के आधार पर प्रति लाख ईएमआई की गणना करेगी। Amount- ₹1 lakh10 Loan Tenure-20 years10 Rate of Interest- 11%-14.5% per annum10 Per Lac EMI-₹1,032-1,28010 Home Loan Eligibility Amount-₹1 Lakh x 18,000/1,032= ₹17.44 Lakhs10 -₹1 Lakh x 18,000/1280= ₹14.06 Lakhs10 So, the eligibility amount falls in the range of ₹14.06 lakhs-17.44 lakhs10</string>
    <string name="text16">पात्रता मानदंड एक पेशे से दूसरे में बदलने के अधीन है: वेतनभोगी आवेदकों के लिए • अधिकतम ऋण राशि पात्रता-संपत्ति के मूल्य का 80% तक • अधिकतम ऋण का कार्यकाल 20 वर्ष या 60 वर्ष की सेवानिवृत्ति की आयु, जो भी पहले हो • ऋण राशि + GST का 1.5% तक प्रोसेसिंग शुल्क • आवेदन की विधि-आप एक व्यक्तिगत या संयुक्त गृह ऋण के लिए आवेदन कर सकते हैं • सार्वजनिक और निजी दोनों क्षेत्रों के वेतनभोगी कर्मचारी होम लोन के लिए पात्र हैं स्व-नियोजित आवेदकों के लिए • अधिकतम ऋण राशि पात्रता-संपत्ति के मूल्य का 80% तक10 • अधिकतम गृह ऋण कार्यकाल -20 वर्ष, लेकिन कार्यकाल आवेदक की आयु 65 वर्ष से अधिक नहीं होना चाहिए • प्रोसेसिंग शुल्क- ऋण राशि के 1.5% तक + जीएसटी • आप या तो एक व्यक्तिगत गृह ऋण आवेदक हो सकते हैं या आवेदक सूची के तहत अपने पति / पत्नी या परिवार के किसी अन्य सदस्य को ला सकते हैं</string>
    <string name="text17">होम लोन की ब्याज दर 11% प्रति वर्ष से लेकर 14.50% प्रति वर्ष है। इसके अलावा, ऋण के लिए लागू प्रसंस्करण शुल्क ऋण राशि का 1.5% है। ऋण लेने के लिए अधिकतम कार्यकाल 20 वर्ष है। आधार कार्ड ऋण के लिए अनिवार्य दस्तावेज वेतनभोगी व्यक्ति: • पहचान प्रमाण: आधार कार्ड / पैन कार्ड / पासपोर्ट / मतदाता पहचान पत्र / ड्राइविंग लाइसेंस • निवास प्रमाण: पासपोर्ट / राशन कार्ड / ड्राइविंग लाइसेंस / उपयोगिता बिल / किराया समझौता • आय प्रमाण: पिछले 3 महीने के बैंक स्टेटमेंट या 6 महीने की बैंक पासबुक • पिछले 3 महीने का वेतन पर्ची या वर्तमान वेतन प्रमाण पत्र। • नवीनतम फॉर्म 161010 • फोटो स्व-नियोजित व्यक्ति • आवेदक या उनकी कंपनी / फर्म का पैन कार्ड • पहचान का प्रमाण: आधार कार्ड / पैन कार्ड / पासपोर्ट / वोटर आईडी कार्ड / ड्राइविंग लाइसेंस • निवास प्रमाण: पासपोर्ट / राशन कार्ड / ड्राइविंग लाइसेंस / उपयोगिता बिल / किराया समझौता • आय प्रमाण: नवीनतम 6 महीने के बैंक स्टेटमेंट • आय गणना, बैलेंस शीट, लाभ और हानि विवरणों के साथ नवीनतम आईटीआर - एक सीए द्वारा प्रमाणित। • व्यापार निरंतरता प्रमाण • फोटो</string>
    <string name="text2">आधार कार्ड अपनी शुरूआत के साथ ही चर्चाओं व विवादों में घिरा रहा है। कुछ लोग इसे सुरक्षित नहीं मानते तो कुछ को यह सुरक्षित लगता है। हमे आये दिन आधार से जुड़ी कुछ अच्छी तो कुछ बुरी खबर मिलती रहती है। लेकिन पिछले दिनों आधार कार्ड से जुड़ी एक बड़ी घटना घटित हुई है जिससे आधार कार्ड से लोगो का विश्वास हट गया है। जिसके कारण अब व्यक्ति की निजता पर सवाल खड़े हो गए हैं। इस पहचान प्रमाण की आसान उपलब्धता और सार्वभौमिक स्वीकृति ने दैनिक जीवन के अधिकांश कार्यों को आसान बना दिया है। इसके अलावा, अद्वितीय संख्या के कारण, भ्रष्टाचार बहुत हद तक कम हो गया है। यहां आधार के सबसे महत्वपूर्ण लाभ हैं  जन धन योजना  10 दिनों में पासपोर्ट  वोटर कार्ड लिंकिंग  नया बैंक खाता खोलना  डिजिटल जीवन प्रमाण पत्र</string>
    <string name="text3">1.आधार कार्ड से ऑनलाइन लोन लेना वैसे तो बहुत ही सिंपल है लेकिन इसके लिए आपको कुछ नियमों का पालन करने की जरूरत होती है 2. अगर आपके डॉक्यूमेंट बिल्कुल सही है तो आपको सरकार के द्वारा बहुत ही जल्दी लोन मिल जाता है. 3.  आपको उनकी सारी शर्तों को मानना पड़ता है. अगर आपके अंदर लोन को वापस करने की काबिलियत है तो आपको बहुत जल्दी ही लोन दे देते हैं.</string>
    <string name="text4">सेवा प्रदाताओं के रूप में ऋण और अन्य वित्तीय सेवाओं के लिए आसान पहुंच, अपने ग्राहकों को नो योर कस्टमर (केवाईसी) प्रलेखन के लिए कहें और आधार आपकी पहचान और नागरिकता साबित करने का सबसे अच्छा तरीका है। नागरिकता, पते, आयु, फोटो और पहचान जैसे कई प्रमाणों के लिए एकल दस्तावेज़। कार्ड का उपयोग ई-केवाईसी, यानी ऑनलाइन सत्यापन के लिए भी किया जा सकता है।</string>
    <string name="text5">Aadhar Card Loan Yojana In Hindi – आज का लगभग हर कार्य के लिए आधार कार्ड अनिवार्य कर दिया गया है | जहाँ भारत सरकार ने सभी सरकारी योजनाओं में आधार कार्ड अनिवार्य कर दिया है | वही अब प्राइवेट संस्था में किसी भी कार्य के लिए आधार कार्ड अनिवार्य कर दिया है | आधार कार्ड से काफी सुविधाएँ भी प्राप्त हो रही हैं | अब आधार कार्ड के माध्यम से हम Aadhar Card Home Loan भी प्राप्त कर सकते हैं | वैसे तो दोस्तों आप बहुत तरह के अलग-अलग लोन ले सकते हैं क्योंकि आज के समय में लोन कंपनी बहुत ही अच्छे अच्छे लोन दे रही है लेकिन जब आप किसी कंपनी से लोन लेते हैं तो उसके लिए कंपनी आप से पहले कुछ जरूरी डाक्यूमेंट्स लेती है और उनके आधार पर ही कंपनी आपको लोन देती है लेकिन कई लोगों के पास उन डाक्यूमेंट्स को पूरा करना बहुत ही कठिन होता है इसलिए वह लोग लोन नहीं ले पाते तो यदि आप भी लोन लेना चाहते हैं या लोन लेने की सोच रहे हैं तू बेवकूफ तू तो मैं आपको बताता हूं कि आप आधार कार्ड के ऊपर लोन ले सकते हैं वह भी बिना किसी दिक्कत के और आपको आधार कार्ड पर बहुत ही आसानी से मिल जाता है. जब आपको ऑनलाइन लोन लेना पड़ता है तो आपसे बहुत डाक्यूमेंट्स कंपनी मांगती है और उस समय आपको बहुत ज्यादा दिक्कत होती है लेकिन अगर आप ऑनलाइन लोन लेना चाहते हैं आधार कार्ड एक एसी चीज़ है. जिससे कि आप बहुत ही आसानी से ऑनलाइन लोन ले सकते है. आप अपना आधार कार्ड इस्तेमाल करके बहुत ही आसानी से ऑनलाइन लोन ले सकते हैं और यदि आप अपने आधार कार्ड से ऑनलाइन लोन लेना चाहते हैं तो आप इस पर 25 लाख रुपए तक का लोन मिल सकता है.</string>
    <string name="text6">Having an Aadhar card is really very important for Indians as the Aadhar card is considered the most important identity card by the government.Let me tell an incident which happened in India - A 5-year-old girl was lost on the busy streets of India. A person saw the girl crying and took the girl to the Police Station. The girl was too small to say anything, so they took her fingerprints and hoped that she had an aadhar card.After they checked their systems, they found out the girls Aadhar Card Status and the small 5-year-old girl was safely sent to her home!</string>
    <string name="text7">यदि आधार कार्ड के माध्यम से आधार कार्ड लोन प्राप्त करना चाहते हैं। तो आप बड़ी आसानी से आधार कार्ड के माध्यम से लोन प्राप्त कर सकते हैं । Aadhar Card Home Loan लिए आपको ऑनलाइन या ऑफलाइन किसी एक तरीके से आवेदन करना होगा। यदि आप ऑनलाइन आवेदन करना चाहते हैं । तो नीचे बताए गए आसान से स्टेप्स को फॉलो करना होगा। जिससे आप Aadhar Card Home Loan के लिए आवेदन कर सकेंगे। - आधार कार्ड से लोन प्राप्त करने के लिए सबसे पहले आपको विभाग की ऑफिशियल वेबसाइट aadharhousing पर जाना होगा । - वेबसाइट पर पहुंचने के पश्चात आपको ड्राप डाउन मेनू में से अपने हिसाब (जिस तरह का लोन आप चाहते है )से अप्लाई फॉर लोन बटन पर क्लिक करना होगा। - जैसे ही आप को इस बटन पर क्लिक करेंगे। आपके सामने एक फॉर्म ओपन होकर आएगा। इसमें आपको अपनी सारी जानकारी सही भरना है। - सभी जानकारी सही करने के पश्चात आपको अपने फॉर्म सबमिट करना होगा । समिट करने के पश्चात मिलने वाली रजिस्ट्रेशन स्लिप को आप अपने पास सुरक्षित रख ले । - फार्म समिट करने के बाद कुछ दिन बाद आपको एक फोन कॉल आएगा। जिसके माध्यम से आपको किसी नजदीकी ऑफिस में डॉक्यूमेंट प्रक्रिया और प्रोसेस पूरा करने के लिए बुलाया जाएगा। - यदि आप लोन प्राप्त करने के योग्य होंगे । और आपमें लोन चुकाने की क्षमता होगी । तो आप को लोन प्रदान कर दिया जाएगा।</string>
    <string name="text8">आधार कार्ड से ऑनलाइन लोन लेने के लिए आपको किन किन बातों का ध्यान रखना पड़ता है और उसकी कुछ नियम होते हैं वह कौन से नियम हैं जिनका आप को पालन करने की जरूरत होती है नीचे हम आपको उन नियमों के बारे में जानकारी दे रहे हैं तो आप ध्यान से पढ़ें 1. आधार कार्ड से ऑनलाइन लोन लेने वाला आदमी लोन को वापस करने में सक्षम होना चाहिए. 2. ऑनलाइन आधार कार्ड से लोन लेने वाला व्यक्ति कम से कम 18 साल की आयु का होना चाहिए 3. ऑनलाइन लोन लेने वाले आदमी के आधार कार्ड में सारी जानकारी बिल्कुल सही होनी चाहिए. 4. लोन लेने वाला आदमी भारत का होना चाहिए. 5. यदि आप आधार कार्ड से ऑनलाइन लोन लेना चाहते हैं तो उसके लिए आपको एक महीने पहले ही लोन के लिए अप्लाई करना पड़ता है उसके बाद आपको सरकार पैसे देती है. 6. यदि आप आधार कार्ड से ऑनलाइन लोन लेना चाहते हैं तो उसके लिए आपके पास अपना मोबाइल नंबर एड्रेस और ईमेल ID होनी चाहिए. 7. आधार कार्ड से ऑनलाइन लोन लेने के लिए सबसे ज्यादा जरूरी आपके पास आपका पैन कार्ड और आपका बैंक अकाउंट जरूर होना चाहिए इसके बाद ही आप आधार कार्ड से ऑनलाइन लोन ले सकते हैं. 8. क्योंकि जब आपके लोन के पैसे आएंगे वह आपको कभी भी सीधे नहीं मिलते ही आपके बैंक अकाउंट के जरिए ही आपके पास आते हैं और इसलिए आपके पास बैंक अकाउंट और पैन कार्ड होना बहुत ही आवश्यक है. हमारे द्वारा बताई गई इन सभी बातों को यदि आप इच्छा पूर्ण पूरा कर लेते हैं तो उसके बाद आपको आधार कार्ड पर ऑनलाइन लोन लेने में बहुत ही आसानी होती है और आप अपने आधार कार्ड से 25 लाख तक का लोन ले सकते हैं.</string>
    <string name="text9">यदि आप अपना घर बनवाना चाहते है । और आपके पास इसके लिए पर्याप्त धनराशी नहीं है । साथ ही यदि आप कोई अपना व्यवसाय शुरू करना चाहते हैं। और आप की आर्थिक स्थिति मजबूत नहीं है । आप अपने व्यवसाय को बढ़ाने के लिए लोन प्राप्त करना चाहते हैं। लेकिन आपके पास किसी प्रॉपर्टी के दस्तावेज नहीं है। जो कि बैंक में लोन प्राप्त करने के लिए गारंटी के तौर पर लगते हैं । तो आप आधार कार्ड पर 25 लाख रुपए तक का लोन प्राप्त कर सकते हैं। आधार कार्ड पर लोन प्राप्त करने के लिए आपको किसी भी प्रकार की कोई गारंटी की आवश्यकता नहीं पड़ती है। आप बैंक या ऑनलाइन ही Aadhar Card Home Loan के लिए आवेदन कर सकते हैं।भारत का कोई भी नागरिक Aadhar Card Home Loan के माध्यम से लोन प्राप्त कर सकता है। भारत सरकार ने देश के नागरिकों की आर्थिक स्थिति मजबूत करने के लिए आधार कार्ड लोन योजना का संचालन कर रहे हैं । इस योजना के अंतर्गत किसानों को छूट भी प्रदान की जाती है।</string>
    <string name="title">ऑनलाइन लोन कैसे प्राप्त करें</string>
    <string name="title1">ऋण देने में आधार कार्ड का महत्व. आधार कार्ड कैसे उपयोगी है?</string>
    <string name="title10">आधार कार्ड पर‌ Online Loans लेने की योग्यता</string>
    <string name="title11">आधार कार्ड का क्या है फायदा?</string>
    <string name="title12">ऑनलाइन लोन लेने के लिए अप्लाई कैसे करें</string>
    <string name="title13">लोन के लिए आवेदन करें</string>
    <string name="title14">चुकौती के लिए न्यूनतम और अधिकतम अवधि</string>
    <string name="title15">आधार आवास वित्त गृह ऋण के बारे में</string>
    <string name="title16">आधार हाउसिंग फाइनेंस होम लोन के लिए अपनी पात्रता की जांच करें</string>
    <string name="title17">अधिकतम वार्षिक प्रतिशत दर</string>
    <string name="title2">आधार से मिल रहे हैं ये फायदे, आपने लिए क्‍या?</string>
    <string name="title3">आधार कार्ड से ऑनलाइन लोन लेने के लिए कैसे अप्लाई करें</string>
    <string name="title4">आधार कार्ड के लाभ एक व्यक्तिगत ऋण और तुरंत व्यक्तिगत ऋण प्राप्त करने के लिए</string>
    <string name="title5">आधार कार्ड लोन ऑनलाइन Apply करें</string>
    <string name="title6">भारत के लिए आधार कार्ड का महत्व</string>
    <string name="title7">आधार कार्ड होम लोन कैसे ले</string>
    <string name="title8">ऑनलाइन आधार कार्ड से लोन लेने की कुछ शर्तें</string>
    <string name="title9">आधार कार्ड होम लोन</string>


    <string name="loan_emi_calculater">Loan Calculater</string>
    <string name="principal_amount">Principal Amount</string>
    <string name="loan_tenure">Loan Tenure</string>
    <string name="month">Month</string>
    <string name="reset_calculation">Reset Calculation?</string>
    <string name="year">Year</string>
    <string name="interest">Interest</string>
    <string name="calculate_your_emi">Calculate Your EMI</string>
    <string name="results_for_your_loan">Results For Your Loan</string>
    <string name="loan_amount">Loan Amount</string>
    <string name="total_amount">Total Amount</string>
    <string name="total_interest">Total Interest</string>
    <string name="interest1">Interest %</string>
    <string name="emi">Emi</string>
    <string name="period_months">Period (Months)</string>


    <string name="pancard">The UIDAI asks the resident to confirm the address (from several address proofs), on which he wants to distribute his Aadhaar letter.  Based on the choice of the resident, UIDAI captures the details as per supporting documents.</string>
    <string name="pancard1"> The Permanent Account Number (PAN) is a ten-digit alphanumeric identifier (identifier) \u200b\u200bissued by the Income Tax Department.  A unique PAN is issued to each such person (ie individual, firm, company etc.).</string>
    <string name="pancard2">All existing assessees or taxpayers or individuals, who are required to file income returns, even if filing on behalf of someone, are required to have PAN.  Any person who wants to do financial or financial transactions, where it is mandatory to file PAN, they also have to have PAN.</string>
    <string name="pancard3">Section 180 of the IT Act, 1971 provides that minor, insane, foolish, retarded, dead and wards of the court and such other persons can be represented through the Represpective Assisi (Representative Assessee).  In such cases: In the application for PAN, details of minor, insane, foolish, retarded, dead and court wards etc. should be given in item 14 of the application for PAN.  .</string>
    <string name="pancard4">The Permanent Account Number (PAN), as the name implies, is a permanent number and does not change.  However, by changing the address, such an officer can change.  Therefore, such changes should be reported to the ITD so that the PAN database of the ITD can be updated.  The applicant can notify the change in address by requesting for a new PAN card or / and filling up the form for change or modification in the PAN data.  This form can be submitted online on any TIN-FC or NSDL e-Governance TIN website.</string>
    <string name="pancard5"> No, it is illegal to obtain / keep more than one PAN, for which Rs.  There may be a fine of 10,000.  Therefore, it is advised not to get / keep more than one pan.</string>
    <string name="pancard6">Yes, as per the procedure laid down by the Income Tax Department, verification of documents submitted by them during PAN application as well as verification of identity and address of PAN applicants can be done by third party.  If found fake, appropriate action can be taken by the Income Tax Department.</string>
    <string name="pancard7">For obtaining e-PAN, it is mandatory to mention the e-mail ID in the PAN application form.", "As per amendment in section 285BA of the Income Tax Act, 1961, specified entities (filers) are required to submit an annual information statement (AIR) in respect of specified financial transactions registered / lodged by them during the financial year, April 1, 2004.  After) to the Income Tax Authority or such other prescribed authority.</string>
    <string name="pancard8">CBDT has appointed Director General of Income Tax (System) as Return Annual Information Return - Administrator \'for the purpose of administering the annual income tax return scheme.</string>
    <string name="pancard9">The organization required to file AIR is required to file a single AIR for the entire organization.</string>
    <string name="pancard10">CBDT has authorized NSDL e-Governance Infrastructure Limited (NSDL) to acquire AIR. NSDL provides offices across its country-wide network to TIN Facilitation Centers (TIN - FCs) and on-line web-based facility.  The data received by TIN-FCS and the data received on-line are collected by NSDL and transmitted to the Income Tax Department.</string>
    <string name="pancard11">The Income Tax Department has introduced a new initiative Call ePAN Card.  Users can use ePAN card facility to get PAN card by applying online.  The ePAN card application feature is free and currently being tested in beta.  To get an e-PAN card, it is mandatory for the applicant to have an Aadhaar card.  Because Aadhaar number of PAN applicant is essentially required to get e-PAN.  Persons already possessing PAN cannot apply for e-PAN.  In addition, ePAN cannot be obtained by the company or LLP or a partnership firm.</string>
    <string name="pancard12">The EPAN card can only be applied by Indian residents to minors and those covered under Section 160 of the Income Tax Act.  Therefore, ePAN card cannot be obtained by Hindu undivided families, firms, trusts, companies etc.  The ePan is created based on the details entered in the Aadhaar card.  Therefore, only people having Aadhaar can get an ePAN and if the details in the Aadhaar card are incorrect, the ePAN will also be inaccurate.  Therefore, in case of rectification, the applicant can visit the official website of UIDAI before applying for ePAN.</string>
    <string name="pancard13">TDS / TCS statements are electronically recorded TDS / TCS quarterly as per Section 200 (3) / 2004C as amended by Finance Act, 2005. As per Income Tax Act, these quarterly statements are submitted from FY 2005-06  Needs to be done; However, it has been suggested by the Income Tax Department that the acceptance of e-TDS / TCS statement pertaining to the financial years before 2008-09 has been closed on TIN. For Quarterly E-TDS Statement Form  The forms used are 24Q, 24Q and 24Q and the Form Number for E-TCS Statement is Quarterly 24EQ. This statement recorded in CD / Pen Drive is Form No. 24A in case of both E-TDS / TCS Statement.  Must be verified with a signature in.</string>
    <string name="pancard14">As per the Income Tax Act, 1971, all the corporates and government deductors / collectors are compulsorily required to file their TDS / TCS details in electronic form ie e-TDS / TCS return.  However, deductors / collectors other than corporate / government can file in any form physical or electronic.</string>
    <string name="pancard15">All drawing and disbursing officers of the Central and State Governments fall under the category of government deductors.</string>
    <string name="pancard16">For this purpose, electronic filing of TDS details notified by the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) as per the scheme on August 24, 2003, e-TDS details should be filed under Section 204 of the Income Tax Act.  CBDT Circular No. 7 dated 19 September 2003 can also be viewed. E-TCS under Section 20C of the Income Tax Act as per the scheme of March 30, 2005 for electronic filing of TCS returns notified by CBDT for this purpose.  The details should be recorded. As per Section 200 (3) / 2004C amended by Finance Act 2005, deductors / collectors are required to file quarterly TDS / TCS details from FY 2005-06 onwards.</string>
    <string name="pancard17">For this purpose, electronic filing of TDS details notified by the Central Board of Direct Taxes (CBDT) as per the scheme on August 24, 2003, e-TDS details should be filed under Section 204 of the Income Tax Act.  CBDT Circular No. 7 dated 19 September 2003 can also be viewed. E-TCS under Section 20C of the Income Tax Act as per the scheme of March 30, 2005 for electronic filing of TCS returns notified by CBDT for this purpose.  The details should be recorded. As per Section 200 (3) / 2004C amended by Finance Act 2005, deductors / collectors are required to file quarterly TDS / TCS details from FY 2005-06 onwards.</string>
    <string name="pancard18">CBDT has appointed Director General of Income Tax (System) as e-filing administrator for the purpose of electronic filing of TDS / TCS statement.</string>
    <string name="pancard19">CBDT has appointed NSDL e-Governance Infrastructure Limited, (NSDL e-Governance), Mumbai as e-TDS / TCS Intermediate. NSDL e-Governance has asked the deductors / collectors to file their e-TDS / TCS details in the country.  TIN Assistance Centers (TIN-FC) have been set up across the country.</string>
    <string name="pancard20">With effect from 12 February 2014, the functionality of submission of foreign remittance details in Form 15CA and its related facilities has been discontinued by TIN and made available on the Income Tax Department\'s e-filing portal www.incometaxindiailing.gov.in.</string>


    <string name="aadhar">Base number A 12-digit random number issued by the UIDAI to all residents of India after completing the verification process laid down by the authority.  is .  Any person of any age who is a resident of India can voluntarily enroll for obtaining Aadhaar number without any gender distinction.\n  A person seeking enrollment has to provide the minimum demographic and biometric information during the enrollment process, which is completely cost-free. \n A person has to enroll for Aadhaar only once and is distinguished through the D-duplication system, only one Aadhaar is created after D-duplication. \n Aadhaar number is authenticated by a cost-effective online method.  It is unique and strong enough to eliminate duplicate and bogus identities and can be used as a basic / primary identity to promote effective delivery, transparency and good governance of various government welfare schemes and services. \n It is the only program of its kind across the world in which people of state of the art digital and online identity are being provided free of cost to the people at large for the service delivery work in the country. Sambhavna has the potential to change. Aadhaar number is also devoid of any kind of intelligence and it is not an external outline of people on the basis of caste, religion, income, health and geography. \n Aadhaar number is proof of identity, however it does not confer citizenship and domicile rights to Aadhaar number holders. Social and financial inclusion, public sector distribution reforms, fiscal budget management to enhance convenience and provide hassle free governance to the people.  Aadhaar is a strategic policy tool for promotion. \n The Aadhaar card can be used as a permanent financial address and to facilitate the financial inclusion of the deprived and weaker sections of the society and hence it is a tool for distributive justice and equality.  Aadhaar Identification platform is one of the major pillars of \\\\\\\"Digital India\\\\\\\" in which a unique identity is provided to every resident of the country.  Base number of  Using this enables the Government of India to reach out to the residents of the country directly for the delivery of various subsidies, benefits and services.</string>
    <string name="aadhar1">Have you changed your name or mobile number recently?  Has your child turned 5 or 15 years old?  You can correct / update your Aadhaar details (demographics and biometrics) at the nearest enrollment / update center.</string>
    <string name="aadhar2">Check the update status of your address using the URN (Update Request Number).  You can check the status of the validation letter of the requested address using the SRN (Service Request Number)</string>
    <string name="aadhar3">Have you moved to a new city?  Or recently changed your address?  Don\'t forget to update your new address in your Aadhaar.  If you have a valid address proof or you have received a validation address (who do not have a valid address proof), you can update your address.</string>
    <string name="aadhar4">Not a valid address proof?  With the help of the validation letter of address sent by UIDAI, residents can still get their address updated in their Aadhaar.</string>
    <string name="aadhar5">The Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) is a statutory authority established by the Government of India under the provisions of the Aadhaar (Targeted Delivery of Financial and Other Subsidies, Benefits and Services) Act, 2016 (\\\"Aadhaar Act, 2016\\\"), Electronics and Information  Under the Ministry of Technology (MEITY) dated 12 July 2016. Prior to its establishment as a statutory authority, UIDAI was the erstwhile Planning Commission (now NITI Aayog) Gazette Notification no.  A-43011/02/2009 - Admin-1 was functioning as an attached office on 28th January, 2009.  Later, on 12 September 2015, UIDAI was associated with the then Department of Information and Technology (DeitY) by the government by amending the Government Work Allocation Rules. UIDAI was established with a unique identity number called \\\"Aadhaar\\\" to all residents of India.  (UID) to provide for (a) elimination of dual and bogus identification and (b) to authenticate and certify it easily and economically. First UID Number A resident of Maharashtra, Nandurbar was released on 29 September 2010.  The Authority has so far provided Aadhaar numbers to more than 120 crore Indian residents. Under the Aadhaar Act 2016, UIDAI Aadhaar enrollment and certification, including the management and operation of all stages of the Aadhaar life cycle, including issuance of Aadhaar numbers and  Responsible for developing policy, procedure and system for conducting authentication and ensuring security of identity information and authentication records. To learn more about UIDAI, please refer to the organizational structure sections of the website</string>
    <string name="aadhar6">E-Aadhaar is a password protected electronic copy of Aadhaar, digitally signed by a competent officer of UIDAI.</string>
    <string name="aadhar7">No .  As your bank information is not shared by the bank with anyone else, no one can know your bank account by knowing your Aadhaar number.  Also, UIDAI or any institution for that matter will not have any information about your bank account.  For example, you can get your mobile number in different places and different authorities like.  Banks give passport authority, income tax department etc.  Does the telecom company have it?  Will your bank information, income tax return etc. be facilitated?  Obviously not!  Similarly, when you provide an Aadhaar number to various service providers, your details remain with the respective service providers and any other including the government or UIDAI.  A single entity will not have access to your personal information spread across various service providers.</string>
    <string name="aadhar8">Routing is the process of allowing users of smart phones, tablets, and other devices running Android mobile operating systems to gain privileged control (known as root access) on various Android subsystems.</string>
    <string name="aadhar9">The UIDAI asks the resident to confirm the address (from several address proofs), on which he wants to distribute his Aadhaar letter.  Based on the choice of the resident, UIDAI captures the details as per supporting documents.</string>
    <string name="aadhar10">The Permanent Account Number (PAN) is a ten-digit alphanumeric identifier (identifier) \u200b\u200bissued by the Income Tax Department.  A unique PAN is issued to each such person (ie individual, firm, company etc.).</string>


    <string name="bike">The thought of buying your desired four-wheeler is itself quite exciting. It is like taking the first big plunge towards a happy and prosperous life. A Bike cuts down your travelling hassles and extra expenses while improving your societal status. But what if you can\'t afford the Bike that you desire to own? You can\'t obviously spend all your savings on your Bike. In such a situation, it is a Bike loan that comes to your help. These are financial advances made by banks or fınancial institutions to help people buy the desired Bike for private or commercial use. At present getting a Bike loan from banks has become very easy and convenient. An easy monthly instalment option is that you need to repay the Bike loan amount. So, this becomes a win-win scenario, where you can act smart by purchasing the ideal Bike for yourself and also avoid the unwanted debt. But when you are availing a Bike loan for the very first time, it is extremely important to know the Bike financing basics before you take the plunge. Hence as a beginner, enlighten yourself with the below-mentioned facts about Bike loan</string>
    <string name="bike1">Eligibility Criteria for a Bike Loan? The basic eligibility particulars to get a Bike loan are as follows: The applicant should be residing in India, be it in rural, semi-urban or urban India. The age limit of the applicant for applying for Bike loan should be at least 18 years or a maximum of 75 years. He/she should have a monthly income of Rs. 10,000. The applicant should be either a salaried or a self-employed individual with at least 2-3 years of working experience. The applicant should have an approved residence with a good amount of parking space inside or outside. He/she should have a residential stability of at least one year.</string>

    <string name="card">What is a Loan on Credit Card?  The uses of credit cards are many.  Starting from cashless transactions to reward points and special deals, you can use credit card anywhere across the globe.  Also, cardholders can avail pre-approved loans on credit cards within or over their credit limit.  Similar to the usual loan schemes, the issuer essentially loans you the amount which you will be able to repay at a later date while being charged a definite interest rate.</string>
    <string name="card1">Features of a Loan on Credit Card Different banks offer comprehensive loan scheme when it comes to loan on credit cards. Listed below are some of the features of loan on credit card. Since most of the loan on credit cards are pre-approved, you need not submit any extra documentation, the loan will be processed and disbursed quickly. With EMI schemes offered by the issuers, you will be able to break your expensive purchases into easy affordable instalments. Some banks also offer loan against other bank\'s credit card through Balance Transfer on EMl where you can transfer the outstanding balance on other credit cards to one credit card and pay the EMI. Issuers also offer you the option of taking a loan within or over your credit limit.</string>
    <string name="card2">Eligibility for Loans on Credit Card? Most credit card loans are unsecured and do not require any collateral for the loan. Hence, the loan is offered to select cardholders only. Issuers have a stringent eligibility criteria when it comes to granting a loan on credit card. The cardholder should have a commendable credit history and a good purchase and repayment pattern to be able to apply for a loan on credit card. Quantum of Loan The quantum of loan on credit card usually depends on the credit limit. Some issuers also offer loan over and above the credit limit where the availed loan amount will not be blocked against the credit limit. Also, starting from a minimum purchase amount of Rs. 2000, you will be able to convert your purchases to loan and pay it as EMIS.</string>
    <string name="card3">Eligibility for Loans on Credit Card? Most credit card loans are unsecured and do not require any collateral for the loan. Hence, the loan is offered to select cardholders only. Issuers have a stringent eligibility criteria when it comes to granting a loan on credit card. The cardholder should have a commendable credit history and a good purchase and repayment pattern to be able to apply for a loan on credit card. Quantum of Loan The quantum of loan on credit card usually depends on the credit limit. Some issuers also offer loan over and above the credit limit where the availed loan amount will not be blocked against the credit limit. Also, starting from a minimum purchase amount of Rs. 2000, you will be able to convert your purchases to loan and pay it as EMIS.</string>


    <string name="headline1">Loan Advise</string>
    <string name="headline2">get loan info</string>
</resources>